Guide to the Mary Butts Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers of Others, 1931-86; Series III; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  - HERBERT FRANK INGRAM
    - Research Files
      - Notebook and loose notes, [1965-84] (Box 22, Folder 318)
      - References to MB in Memoirs and Autobiographies, notes and copies, [1920s-70s] (Box 22, Folder 319)
      - Appreciations of MB by other writers, 1937-65 (Box 22, Folder 320)
      - Book reviews written by MB, 1931-34 (Box 22, Folder 321)
      - Reviews of MB's writings, 1931-71 (Box 22, Folder 322)
        Also includes reviews of Anthony Butts' Curious Relations and William Plomer's Museum Pieces
      - Ashe of Rings dust jacket, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 323)
      - Copies of drawings of MB, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 324)
        Reproduction of Cocteau drawing MB used as 1931 Christmas card, and photocopy of drawing by unknown artist
        See also: Oversize, Box 24, Folder 337
      - Copies of death certificates of MB and Anthony Butts, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 325)
      - Butts and Briggs families, [1960s] (Box 22, Folder 326)
      - Photographs of The Salterns, [pre-1906] (Box 22, Folder 327)
  - STANLEY REVELL
    - Research notes, 1986, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 328)
- Oversize, 3.32; (2 boxes)
  - Notebook/Diary of MB (in Series I), 1922-23 (Box 23, Folder 329)
  - Portrait of [Mary Butts?] by unknown (in Series I), [ca. 1920] (Box 23, Folder 330)
  - Article by Mary Colville-Hyde about Holbein portraits of Sir William & Lady Butts, Apollo (in Series II), 1935 Jul (Box 23, Folder 331)
  - Article on supposed Holbein portrait of Sir William Butts, Illustrated London News (in Series II), 1930 Mar 8 (Box 23, Folder 332)
  - Photograph of the Butts family on the yacht "Vanity" (in Series II), [1890s] (Box 23, Folder 333)
  - Photograph of Mary Butts, then Mrs. Rodker (in Series II), 1919 (Box 24, Folder 334)
  - John Rodker's copy of the legal "Settlement in favour of Miss Camilla Rodker" (in Series II), 1924 Sep 19 (Box 24, Folder 335)
  - Portrait of Mary Butts as Saint Cecilia, by Irlam Briggs (in Series II), [ca. 1905-10] (Box 24, Folder 336)
  - Copy of drawing of Mary Butts, by unknown artist (in Series III), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 337)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 27 (Box 25, Folder 338)
  - Box 2, folder 46 (Box 25, Folder 339)
  - Box 13, folder 192 (Box 25, Folder 340)
  - Box 15, folder 199 (Box 25, Folder 341)
  - Box 15, folder 203 (Box 25, Folder 342)
  - Box 16, folder 214 (Box 25, Folder 343)
  - Box 16, folder 215 (Box 25, Folder 344)
  - Box 16, folder 216 (Box 25, Folder 345)
  - Box 16, folder 232 (Box 25, Folder 346)
  - Box 16, folder 233 (Box 25, Folder 347)
  - Box 17, folder 243 (Box 25, Folder 348)
  - Box 18, folder 257 (Box 25, Folder 349)
  - Box 18, folder 270 (Box 25, Folder 350)
  - Box 19, folder 274 (Box 25, Folder 351)
  - Box 19, folders 275-277 (Box 25, Folder 352)
  - Box 19, folder 279 (Box 25, Folder 353)
  - Box 19, folder 281 (Box 25, Folder 354)
  - Box 19, folder 282 (Box 25, Folder 355)
  - Box 19, folder 283 (Box 25, Folder 356)
  - Box 19, folder 285 (Box 25, Folder 357)
  - Box 19, folder 286 (Box 25, Folder 358)
  - Box 19, folder 287 (Box 25, Folder 359)
  - Box 19, folder 288 (Box 25, Folder 360)
  - Box 19, folder 289 (Box 25, Folder 361)
  - Box 21, folder 311 (Box 25, Folder 362)
  - Box 21, folder 313 (Box 25, Folder 363)
  - Box 21, folder 314 (Box 25, Folder 364)
  - Box 21, folder 316 (Box 25, Folder 365)
  - Box 21, folder 317 (Box 25, Folder 366)
  - Box 22, folder 319 (Box 25, Folder 367)
  - Box 22, folder 320 (Box 25, Folder 368)
  - Box 22, folder 322 (Box 25, Folder 369)
  - Box 22, folder 326 (Box 25, Folder 370)
- Restricted Fragile Oversize, 2; (1 box)
  - Box 1, folder 31 (Box 26, Folder 371)
  - Box 15, folder 199 (Box 26, Folder 372)
  - Box 16, folders 214-215 (Box 26, Folder 373)
  - Box 18, folder 264 (Box 26, Folder 374)
  - Box 18, folder 271 (Box 26, Folder 375)
  - Box 21, folder 311 (Box 26, Folder 376)
  - Box 21, folder 314 (Box 26, Folder 377)
  - Box 22, folder 319 (Box 26, Folder 378)
  - Box 22, folder 326 (Box 26, Folder 379)